Anselm Joseph

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

www.an23lm.me

+1 (872) 258-5803

an23lm@gmail.com

github.com/an23lm 😱

linkedin.com/in/an23lm in

Chicago, Illinois 📍

A self-starter, quick learner, and an organized creative developer, with experience in leading projects end-to-end, including requirement analysis, UI/UX design, backend architecture, and frontend development; currently pursuing a Master's Degree in Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Client-side

React & React Native

HTML, CSS & JavaScript

Tailwind CSS

iOS, iPadOS & macOS - Swift

Android - Kotlin & Java

UI Design - Figma

Server-side

Google Cloud, Firebase, & AWS

MongoDB, Firestore, MySQL, & Redis

Next.js

Spring Boot - Java

Flask, SkLearn - Python

EDUCATION

Illinois Institute of Technology

Master of Engineering in AI for Computer Vision and Control

New Horizon College of Engineering

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science

EXPERIENCE

MOLEX PVT. LTD.

DEC 2019 - AUG 2022

Full Stack Developer

Responsible for developing enterprise IoT technologies with a focus on high availability & reliability. Entailed big data processing and real time analytics.

CBREX PVT. LTD.

AUG 2017 - DEC 2019

Product Engineer 1

AUG 2017 - SEPT 2019

Deeply involved in developing the product of the technology enabled start-up from the ground up as an early hire. Contributed to many early fundamental technological decisions. Involved in developing mobile applications, website, and backend. Contributed to the growth of the technology team.

Lead Data Analyst

OCT 2017 - DEC 2019

Responsible for building the company's analytics system for internal metrics tracking to meet stakeholder's requirements.

PROJECTS

EARTHEN SHADE

FREELANCE PROJECT - SEPT 2022

Responsible for developing the entire technology for an e-commerce platform to meet the client's requirements.

Pre-release Website: earthen-shade.vercel.app

TEA-PLATES.JS

PERSONAL PROJECT - JUN 2019

An Open-Source, templating engine written in JavaScript. Initially written for use on CBREX's website.

GitHub: github.com/an23lm/tea-plates.js

TABLE MODERNO

PERSONAL PROJECT - FEB 2019

An Open-Source, simple, powerful, and modern implementation of tables for the web written in JavaScript and CSS. Initially written for use on CBREX's website.

GitHub: github.com/an23lm/Table-Moderno

Find more of my open source work here



2024

github.com/an23lm